<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Geekeries | Hack and frogs]]></title>
  <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/categories/geekeries/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-09T23:05:57+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://picsoung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicolas Grenié]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@nicolasgrenie.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disable comment box on Facebook like button]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/10/31/disable-comment-box-on-facebook-like-button/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-31T02:14:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/10/31/disable-comment-box-on-facebook-like-button</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/1-Facebook.png" alt="1-Facebook.png" title="1-Facebook.png, oct. 2011" /></p>




<p>Having a website is cool, having a social website is better :)
SEO is not the only way to drive traffic to your website anymore, you need a social presence to get more people coming on your site.
If are looking for an easy way to make your website social you can use services like <a href="http://www.addthis.com/" hreflang="en" title="AddThis">AddThis</a>, with a small line of javascript, your users will be able to share your website on main social networks.</p>




<p>That's super easy but you might be the kind of person who likes to manage everything and want to code your own stuff.</p>




<p>Implementing a like button is also super simple go on this page
http://developers.facebook.com/docs/reference/plugins/like/</p>




<p>And get the code you need to implement to have a nice-looking Like button :)</p>




<p>Recently Facebook add a comment functionality but you may want to disable it.
Add these few lines of CSS and the comment box won't show up&nbsp;:</p>




<pre>[CSS]
.fb_edge_widget_with_comment{
  position: absolute;
}

.fb_edge_widget_with_comment span.fb_edge_comment_widget iframe.fb_ltr {
  display: none !important;
}
</pre>




<p>Now you have old-style like button without a comment box :)
Have fun "hacking" Facebook :)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create a startup webpage in less than 1 hour - Tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/03/15/create-a-startup-webpage-in-less-than-1-hour-tools/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-15T04:10:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/03/15/create-a-startup-webpage-in-less-than-1-hour-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a <a href="http://startupweekend.org/" hreflang="en" title="StartupWeekend">StartupWeekend</a> alumni I know there are many things you have to do during the weekend in to order to present a nice demo to the audience. One of the important things to do is building a website to present your product and get known on the web.
I wish I had at that time an article with a compilation of tools to use and an easy-to-follow tutorial about how to use these tools.
This article is the first part of the tutorial, I will present the tools we will use in the second part.</p>




<p>Who you should read this article&nbsp;: if you are in a <a href="http://startupweekend.org/" hreflang="en" title="StartupWeekend">StartupWeekend</a>, if you are building your startup and don't want to spend to much time on the website, if you have a startup idea and want to get known or if you are curious :)</p>




<p>Why you should not read this article&nbsp;: if you think that ninjas are better</p>




<p>As a new startup you will need a custom domain name with a hosting space, a landing page to invite future users to sign-up for a beta, a blog and a Twitter account.</p>




<h2>1. Host your website and buy a custom domain name</h2>




<p>You have many offers to host your website and get your own domain name, you can pick the one you prefer. Following this tutorial you will not need a lot of space but think one step further to when you will need space for you real website.
I personally recommend <a href="http://www.kqzyfj.com/click-5069681-10605229?cm_mmc=CJ-_-3294521-_-5069681-_-Get%20Unlimited%20Web%20Hosting" hreflang="en" title="CoolHandle">CoolHandle</a> because they have a $5/mo offer with unlimited space and bandwith, their support his amazing (they always replied in less than 24hours), they give a FREE domain with any hosting plan, plus they have a built-in option for one of the services we will use.</p>


<p><a href="http://www.dpbolvw.net/click-5069681-10605229?cm_mmc=CJ-_-3294521-_-5069681-_-Get%20Unlimited%20Web%20Hosting">Get UNLIMITED Web Hosting Now</a><img src="http://www.ftjcfx.com/image-5069681-10605229" width="1" height="1" border="0"/></p>

<p>To get $50 off on Coolhandle offers use the code&nbsp;: <strong>zc06956</strong></p>




<p>Once you have you have your own .com and hosting plan you can go to the next step.</p>




<h2>2. Create an account on a wonderful blog platform</h2>




<p><img src="http://posterous.com/images/posterous-medium.png" alt="" /></p>




<p>Blog platform&nbsp;? Really&nbsp;? Yes&nbsp;! It is not like Blogger or Skyblog which are for teenagers&nbsp;; do not worry! We will use <a href="http://posterous.com" hreflang="en" title="Posterous">Posterous</a>, which is the new fashion in blog platforms for startups. It is very understandable when you see how easy it is to post on the blog.
<a href="http://posterous.com" hreflang="en" title="Posterous">Posterous</a> is very powerful; you can post just by sending an email, and that is very useful when you need your team to post on the blog. Another interesting feature is the connection with social networks. <a href="http://posterous.com" hreflang="en" title="Posterous">Posterous</a> lets you update your Facebook page, your Twitter account, Reddit... automatically when you post something. It gains you a significant amount of time&nbsp;!</p>




<p>So sign-up here&nbsp;: <a href="http://posterous.com" hreflang="en" title="Posterous">Posterous</a></p>




<h2>3. Create a <a href="http://cloudflare.com/" hreflang="en" title="CloudFlare">Cloudflare</a> account to manage your DNS</h2>




<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/.cloudfare_homepage_m.jpg" alt="cloudfare home" style="float:left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" title="cloudfare home, oct. 2010" /></p>




<p><a href="http://cloudflare.com/" hreflang="en" title="CloudFlare">Cloudflare</a> is a San Francisco based startup that permits you to speed up your website and protect it against spammers. It is very efficient&nbsp;: usually 65% faster. It is very easy and quick to configure with your domain, which we will see in the next part. It also permits you to manage your DNS as a professional. And everything is FREE&nbsp;! You can upgrade your account to a pro account if free features are not enough.</p>




<p>If you have a <a href="http://www.kqzyfj.com/click-5069681-10605229?cm_mmc=CJ-_-3294521-_-5069681-_-Get%20Unlimited%20Web%20Hosting" hreflang="en" title="CoolHandle">CoolHandle</a> account you can configure <a href="http://cloudflare.com/" hreflang="en" title="CloudFlare">Cloudflare</a> from your Cpanel otherwise we will see how to create and configure your account in the next part.</p>




<h2>4. Ask for a <a href="http://launchrock.com/" hreflang="en" title="LaunchRock">LaunchRock</a> invitation</h2>




<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/LaunchRock_Logo_-_Black-Red_Fully_Transparent.png" alt="" /></p>




<p><a href="http://launchrock.com/" hreflang="en" title="LaunchRock">LaunchRock</a> is the new must-have for startups&nbsp;! It is the winner of the <a href="http://startupweekend.org/" hreflang="en" title="StartupWeekend">StartupWeekend</a> of Philadelphia. With LaunchRock you have a simple page where users will be able to sign-up to get early access to your website, and share a referral link on social networks. It is again easy to configure and you have nothing to do besides customize the page. It is super powerful to see which successful startups already use it&nbsp;: <a href="http://Zaarly.com" hreflang="en" title="Zaarly">Zaarly</a>, <a href="http://ditchThetourbus" hreflang="en" title="DitchTheTourBus">DitchTheTourBus</a>, <a href="http://launchrock.com/" hreflang="en" title="LaunchRock">LaunchRock</a>...</p>




<p>If you do not have an invite yet and you are attending a <a href="http://startupweekend.org/" hreflang="en" title="StartupWeekend">StartupWeekend</a>, just email sw <a href="[@" title="[@">[@</a>] launchrock.com and they will send you an early invite.
If thiq is not your case you can still sign up on <a href="http://launchrock.com/" hreflang="en" title="LaunchRock">LaunchRock</a> and wait for an invitation or email the team and explain your project.</p>




<h2>5. Create your social network identity</h2>




<p>That is the easiest step. You just have to create a <a href="http://twitter.com" hreflang="en" title="Twitter">Twitter</a> account, a <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/create.php" hreflang="en" title="facebook">Facebook</a> page, a Youtube account if you have videos, Foursquare, etc...</p>




<p>If you read this, that means you have hopefully completed the 5 previous steps and you have all the tools you need to create your startup webpage.</p>




<p>Let's go to step 2&nbsp;: Link all the tools together (coming soon)</p>




<p><em>Special Thanks to Kirsten Pertersen (St. Olaf 2011) who helped me with my english grammar</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geek - Où je suis passé à Cloudflare]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2010/10/06/geek-ou-je-suis-passe-a-cloudflare/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-06T06:24:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2010/10/06/geek-ou-je-suis-passe-a-cloudflare</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/.cloudfare_homepage_s.jpg" alt="cloudflare home" style="float:right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" title="cloudfare home, oct. 2010" />Vous n’avez certainement rien remarqué et c’est bien normal… J'ai découvert Cloudflare après la lecture d'un <a href="http://fr.techcrunch.com/2010/09/30/techcrunch-disrupt-ce-qui-sest-passe-a-lautre-cote-de-latlantique-la-meilleure-start-up/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+francaistechcrunch+%28TechCrunch+en+Francais%29" hreflang="fr">article</a> de Techcrunch France à propos de la conférence Techcrunch Disrupt qui s'est déroulée du 27 au 29 septembre dernier à San Francisco. Le principe de ces trois jours de conférence est de réunir start-up et entrepreneurs du web afin de faire connaître les projets innovants en recherche de fonds. À cette occasion quelques boîtes françaises (<a href="http://dismoiou.fr/" hreflang="fr">Dismoiou</a>, <a href="http://www.boosket.com/en" hreflang="en">Boostket</a>, <a href="http://kwaga.com/" hreflang="fr">Kwaga</a>, <a href="http://www.stribe.com/" hreflang="fr">Stribe</a> et<a href="http://www.wozaik.com/bienvenue" hreflang="fr"> Wozaik</a>) avaient fait le voyage mais n'ont malheureusement pas remportées la récompense de 50 000 $ attribuée à la meilleure des 27 start-up sélectionnées.</p>




<p>C'est <a href="http://www.qwiki.com/" hreflang="en">Qwiki</a> qui s'est hissé sur la première marche du podium. Un service qui devrait révolutionner notre manière de consommer Internet. J'avoue ne pas avoir été spécialement bluffé…
Sur les autres marches on retrouvait <a href="http://www.pinger.com/content/int/" hreflang="en">Pinguer</a> qui édite des applications mobiles et<a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/home.html" hreflang="en"> Cloudflare</a> la fameuse application que j'ai adopté.</p>




<p>Je ne sais pas trop d'ailleurs pourquoi j'ai passé le pas. C'est assez contradictoire j'ai tendance à pas écrire souvent ici mais par contre j'adore ajouter des fonctionnalités. C'est comme ça que j'ai installé les outils de statistiques Google Analytics au début du mois de septembre et Xiti un peu plus tard.</p>




<p>Cloudflare s'annonce comme quelque chose qui doit accélérer notre site. Le bourrer d'amphét' pour qu'il explose le 100m du chargement. Après l'installation j'ai effectivement eu l'impression que ça allait plus vite. Comme à chaque fois cela reste subjectif. On m'aurait dit ça envoie un message aux extraterrestres je l'aurais peut-être cru.</p>




<p>Quoi qu'il en soit c'est très facile d'installation. Il suffit de créer un compte en renseignant l'adresse de son site. Ils s'occupent de trouver les domaines liés et de demander lesquels on veut faire bénéficier de la "supercharge". Pour ma part je l'ai activé sur tout mon domaine nicolasgrenie.com et ses sous domaines pro et blog. On a plus qu'à changer les DNS de son domaine pour les faire pointer chez Cloudflare. Et paf ! C’est fini, à nous la vitesse !</p>




<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/.cloudfare_dashboard_s.jpg" alt="cloudflare dashboard" style="float:left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" title="cloudflare dashboard, oct. 2010" />L'idée est simple ils jouent les intermédiaires pour empêcher les vilains visiteurs de mettre le barouf chez vous. Comment&nbsp;? Si quelqu'un accède trop de fois d'un coup à une même page on lui demande de remplir un captcha. Comme c'est un robot y peut pas… L'IP est donc mis en zone de quarantaine, il sera demandé une IP à chaque fois qu'elle essaye de se connecter.</p>




<p>D'après les stats fournies pour l'instant après 5 jours d'utilisation cela m'a permis d'arrêter 4 bots spammeurs, d'économiser 1 854 requêtes, 27MB de bande passante, et les pages se chargent en 0.27sec au lieu de 0.37 \o/ Je suis un homme heureux :)</p>




<p>L'avantage de tout ça c'est que le service est Gratuit, ce qui est plutôt pas mal pour ce genre de service. Comme beaucoup de sites actuellement le système est de type Freemium il faudra donc payer une petite obole pour bénéficier d'autres services.</p>




<p>J'ai donc apprécié la simplicité d'installation, le côté user-friendly de l'interface du Dashboard ainsi que les services (sécurité, accélération, disponibilité H24 de mon site).
On notera également que les concepteurs de Cloudflare font parti du projet Project Honey Pot qui est une espèce de grosse base de données temps réel des spammeurs mis à jour automatiquement grâce aux webmasters qui ont installé ce service sur leur site.</p>




<p>À tester donc amis webmestres !</p>




<p>PS&nbsp;: marre de flickr… j'a installé un plugin gallery au blog donc pour sûr des photos de l'automne américain arrivent prochainement</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tron Legacy, la BO et l'ASCII Art]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2010/09/08/tron-legacy-la-bo-et-l-ascii-art/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-08T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2010/09/08/tron-legacy-la-bo-et-l-ascii-art</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nan toujours pas&nbsp;? Arf vraiment dommage car ce film fait partie de la multitudes de film geek à voir. L'original Tron est sorti en 1982. C'est l'histoire toute bête d'un programmeur qui rentre sans son ordinateur pour y trouver ses programmes. À l'intérieur, un programme initialement prévu pour jouer aux échecs s'est développé et a pris le contrôle. Le synopsis est assez simple mais enrobé d'un visuel totalement futuriste et hors du commun. Une belle métaphore de l'ordinateur et du transit des informations.</p>




<p>Le jeu dérivé du film est en fait lié à une partie du film où des protagonistes s'affrontent sur des <em>Light Cycle</em>, sorte de motos du futur qui n'avancent qu'en ligne droite en formant des murs sur leur passage. Croiser un mur est fatal. Votre but est donc de piéger vos adversaires sans tomber dans les leurs.</p>




<p>Tron Legacy sera donc la suite (tant attendue !?). Elle devrait sortir pour les fêtes aux USA et en février 2011 en France. Ce film sera certainement l'un des films qui marquera la fin de l'année. Il y a du beau monde pour ce nouvel opus. Daft Punk à la BO pour signer leur grand retour, Jeff Bridges acteur déjà présent dans le premier Tron ou encore Olivia Wilde (Docteur House). Le tout servi par la super production de Disney.</p>




<p>À vrai dire je suis impatient de voir ce que va donner ce film, aussi bien pour la technique que l'histoire mais surtout pour la musique des Daft Punk&nbsp;! En parlant BO vous pouvez déjà en avoir un aperçu&nbsp;: <a href="http://www.tronsoundtrack.com/" hreflang="en">tronsoundtrack.com</a></p>




<p>Easter Egg&nbsp;: sur la page faites clique-droit -&gt; voir les sources, il y a une surprise pour vous :)</p>




<p>La Bande-annonce</p>


<div id='blogvision' style='width:420px; height:335px'><object width='100%' height='100%'><param name='movie' value='http://www.allocine.fr/blogvision/19129167'></param><param name='allowFullScreen' value='true'></param><param name='allowScriptAccess' value='always'></param><embed src='http://www.allocine.fr/blogvision/19129167' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' width='100%' height='100%' allowFullScreen='true' allowScriptAccess='always'/></object></div>




<p><a href="http://www.allocine.fr/film/fichefilm_gen_cfilm=29233.html" hreflang="fr">La page allociné</a></p>




<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1104001/" hreflang="en">IMDB</a></p>




<p><em>PS: ASCII art trouvé à partir du twitter de <a href="http://twitter.com/insomniedugeek" hreflang="fr">@insomniedugeek</a></em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mir:ror mon beau mir:ror]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2010/06/18/mir-ror-mon-beau-mir-ror/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-18T20:14:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2010/06/18/mir-ror-mon-beau-mir-ror</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Non pas que je rêve de jouer à faire comme la marâtre de Blanche Neige qui questionnait son miroir à la recherche de la beauté... Mais j'ai un miroir intelligent moi :) Un mir:ror&nbsp;! Pour les incultes c'est une espèce de coupelle de plastique qui renferme un lecteur de puces RFID. Lecteur de quoi&nbsp;? De Réfidé&nbsp;! ces petites puces que l'on commence à trouver un peu partout, dans les pass Optymo ou Navigo, les badges d'accès ou encore dans le passeport biométrique des chats. Au Japon elles sont déjà très répandues.</p>




<p>Mais à quoi que ca sert se bidule&nbsp;?</p>




<p>Euuuuh... un peu à tout et encore à rien. Le mir:ror de Violet est fourni avec quelques applications qui permettent de mettre à jour un profil Facebook, envoyer un mail, lancer une musique sur iTunes ou jouer à pile ou face. C'est pas tellement pour ces applications que j'ai craqué, mais bien pour ses potentialités. Il reste encore pleins d'applications à inventer autour de ce périphérique et j'ai quelques petites idées derrière la tête que j'aimerais bien mettre en oeuvre dès l'été.</p>




<p>Je pense que Tiwix est content d'avoir de nouveaux amis autour de lui en plus de Pinkyz et Purplyz déjà arrivés à Noël dernier. Car avec le Mir:ror il y avait deux autres nanoz:tag et des ztamp:s, autant de nouvelles puces RFID à configurer.</p>




<p>Je m'en vais de suite faire mumuse avec ce bijou de technologie de Violet.
Je vous laisse avec Tiwix et ses copains qui découvrent le petit nouveau.</p>




<p><a href="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4026/4712404484_2888c45915_t.jpg"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4026/4712404484_2888c45915_m.jpg" alt="IMGP2070" /></a></p>




<p><em><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/picsoung/4712404484/">IMGP2070</a></em></p>




<p><a href="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4062/4712436352_2ab7d73c19_t.jpg"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4062/4712436352_2ab7d73c19_m.jpg" alt="IMGP2073" /></a></p>




<p><em><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/picsoung/4712436352/">IMGP2073</a></em></p>




<p><a href="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4034/4711801889_4f24a18d37_t.jpg"><img src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4034/4711801889_4f24a18d37_m.jpg" alt="IMGP2074" /></a></p>




<p><em><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/picsoung/4711801889/">IMGP2074</a></em></p>




<p><a href="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1268/4712439660_cd0c3fdfb0_t.jpg"><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1268/4712439660_cd0c3fdfb0_m.jpg" alt="IMGP2081" /></a></p>




<p><em><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/picsoung/4712439660/">IMGP2081</a></em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
