<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: In the Valley | Hack and frogs]]></title>
  <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/categories/in-the-valley/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-27T22:21:04-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://picsoung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicolas Grenié]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@nicolasgrenie.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I am a Buspreneur - Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2012/03/20/i-am-a-buspreneur-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T23:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2012/03/20/i-am-a-buspreneur-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WoW! Just wow ! i just get back from the crazy SXSW, or for those who don't know: "the Las Vegas of startup world". It's been an amazing experience from Day 1 till the end. I can't wait to tell you about what happened ;)</p>




<h2>The StartupBus</h2>




<p>As you may have read in my <a href="http://picsoung.github.io/index.php?post/I-am-on-a-Bus%21">previous post</a> I took the StartupBus to go to Austin. We left San Francisco, CA on Tuesday in the early morning to arrive Austin, TX on Friday evening.</p>




<h2>Day 1</h2>




<p><img src="http://50.56.192.33/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/silicon_valley_bus_s.png" alt="" /></p>




<p>We were all supposed to meet at the StartupHouse at 6 am to pack our stuff and start the journey to Austin. I had a really time to wake up, I barely spelt the weekend before, I was at another hackathon where we've build a tip planner called <a href="http://bit.ly/easymapr" hreflang="en">EasyMapr</a>. Apparently some other Buspreneurs attended the same Hackathon, so we were all on the same page in terms of hours of sleep. But ready to rock !</p>




<p>Josh, our conductor organized hackathons and a launch party the week before our departure but I was not able to attend. So I did not know anybody. It's part of the magic of the StartupBus adventure ;)</p>




<p>While we were meeting each other prior to departure we were surrounded by cameras from TechCrunch and another special guest : Mr. <a href="http://scobleizer.com/" hreflang="en" title="Scobleizer">Robert Scoble</a> in person.</p>




<p>For those who don't' know Robert Scoble, he is working for <a href="http://rackspace.com" hreflang="en">Rackspace</a> (a hosting company) and helps startups to get traction thanks to interviews and blog posts on his high-traffic Blog. He is sometimes solicited to be a judge or an advisor during startup competitions. He was on the bus with us until we stopped in Santa Monica. It was a chance for us to have him onboard to receive quick feedbacks about what we were building.</p>




<p>We had a long way to ride to Austin, but thanks to the sponsor of the Sillicon Valley bus, <a href="http://elance.com" hreflang="en" title="Elance">Elance</a> we had a nice breakfast at their place. We also met Buspreneurs from the Stanford bus. On our way to Elance we all present ourselves in the bus. I was really impressed by the variety of skillsets and by all the talented people. Most of my Buspreneurs fellows were working in a startup or already create one/many. It was also a nice international crowd with several Australians, a German and a French (myself).</p>




<p>After our nice breakfast it was time for us to ride to Los Angeles. As soon as we get onboard we started the pitch session.</p>




<p>Everybody had 1min to explain his project and vision. I think that we all pitched something. They were ideas like a StartTrek alarm clock that gives you a summary of your day in the morning, or a website to create your own cereals and many others.</p>




<p>I pitched the idea for a Taxi-sharing service, where people can split the taxi bill by sharing a cab with somebody that's going somewhere around the place you are going to. Like most of us I was not strongly attached to my idea and I was very open to work on someone else project.</p>




<p>At the end of the pitches (~40 pitches) we stopped to form groups and start working.</p>




<p>Most of the groups were formed pretty quickly, and 6 projects really emerged after the stop.</p>




<p>StartupBus Silicon Valley projects:</p>




<p>Beeliner - Find which events the people you want to meet are attending
Cerealize - Your custom cereals delivered at your door.
Expensiev - Expenses tracking for freelancers
Gaggle - mobile app that filters your social feeds to only people you care about in that instan
HipType - Dynamic content for iBooks Author, analytics and social media integration
Kinetic.ly - Tools for motion analysis</p>




<p>As soon as we went back on the bus we were all ready to brainstorm and work on our on projects. By the end of the day we had to stop in Santa Monica to do quick Customer validation survey on the street, so we better have a good idea of our product by that time.</p>




<p>I joined to the team <a href="http://cerealize.com" hreflang="en">Cerealize</a> because I was very excited by the quick brainstorm we had when we were forming teams. I did not know before that cereals were a big deal in America. That helped me to understand to full potential of this project, much bigger than what I thought during the pitch session.</p>




<p>The video of the first day thanks to John from TechCrunch</p>




<script src="http://player.ooyala.com/player.js?height=360&embedCode=9kM3VwMzrv1ETsstWxGMT7K8E9jEdte-&deepLinkEmbedCode=9kM3VwMzrv1ETsstWxGMT7K8E9jEdte-&width=640"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I am on a Bus!]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2012/03/06/i-am-on-a-bus/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T01:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2012/03/06/i-am-on-a-bus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://50.56.192.33/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/silicon_valley_bus_s.png" alt="" /></p>




<p>To be honest I am not yet on the Bus, it's just a matter of time now. In 6 hours I will be seating on THE bus, THE <a href="http://StartupBus.com" hreflang="en" title="StartupBus">StartupBus</a> departing from San Francisco to go to Austin for SXSWi. I think I have not realized yet that I will part of this crazy adventure.</p>




<p>For those who have not heard of <a href="http://StartupBus.com" hreflang="en" title="StartupBus">StartupBus</a>  and SXSWi before let me try to explain.</p>




<h3>SXSWi</h3>




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/vkQh4Sn89yw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<p>Helds in Austin Texas, SXSW is a global festival. SXSW stands for South by SouthWest and the little i is for interactive.
It started in 1987 as a music festival and then they add music and more recently an interactive track for emerging new technology stuff. It happens every year in Austin and it is always bigger and bigger in terms of number of attendees and performances :)</p>




<p>From a tech point of view it is the place to be if you are part of this world. During 4 days, all the most important guys on earth that are building the Web/App/Mobile world will be there. Either by being speaking in one of the many panels of the official track or by throwing other events in the city.</p>




<p>It is the place to go for grown startups who want to promote their product and new features but for sure it is really the place to be for new startup that need traction and press.</p>




<p>I think that all the web entrepreneurs in the world have a "SXSW Launch plan" in their mind. There is a lot of competitions to get the attention of the early-adopters techie attendees, and only few happy ending stories.
Examples ? in 2007 <a href="http://twitter.com" hreflang="en">Twitter</a> get a lot of early traction event if they did not launch there, Foursquare launched a SXSWi in 2009 or <a href="www.foodspotting.com" hreflang="en" title="FoodSpotting">FoodSpotting</a> in 2010.</p>




<p>This year everybody will be looking around for the next big thing. And for short period the most popular pickup line will be "I was using blabla before it was cool at SXSW".
Early adopters have a though life ;)</p>




<p>I planned to install at least a dozen of new apps on my ipad, and sign up to a bunch of other websites.
I heard so many thing about this festival, I am really excited about it. For a wannabe entrepreneur its all the fairy that I kid could have in Disneyland.</p>




<p>And to add more fun and WOWness to this adventure I will be joining the Silicon Valley <a href="http://StartupBus.com" hreflang="en" title="StartupBus">StartupBus</a>.</p>




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2f70gxTUt5U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<p>The idea of the <a href="http://StartupBus.com" hreflang="en" title="StartupBus">StartupBus</a> started with a friend joke between Australian guys : roadtrip to SF with friend with the challenge of building a startup in the same time. The first <a href="http://StartupBus.com" hreflang="en" title="StartupBus">StartupBus</a> trip went to SF to Austin in 2010 on a bus with wifi. At Austin six projects were pitched to local investors. In 2011 Chicago, Clevevand, NYC and Miami joined the movement. For 2012 11 buses will travel across US and Mexico to  get to Austin with entrepreneurs on board.</p>




<p>Or should I say Buspreneurs :) Buspreneurs are a mix of business guys and coders who have cool ideas about ways to make the world better.</p>




<p>They all have 3-4 days to make those ideas real project and viable businesses. When buses arrive in Austin it is time to meet other Buspreneurs, the next two days will be semi-finals and finals between all the buses.
I just know the basic elevator pitch about the <a href="http://StartupBus.com" hreflang="en" title="StartupBus">StartupBus</a>, the rest will be the experience itself and I will find about it pretty soon :)</p>




<p>As a hacker and a Hackathon addict I am really excited. It's all about building a real business and not only a hack to have fun with a cool API.</p>




<p>I am sure I will learn a lot of stuff from the people that I will meet during this trip.</p>




<p>Let's get started ! Few hours away to a big step to the unknown ;)</p>




<p>PS: get ready to get spammed on your Twitter Timeline with #sxsw if you are not there tweet with #notatsxsw ;)</p>




<p>PSS: check http://startupbus.com as often as you can ;)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to create a startup webpage in less than 1 hour - part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2012/02/03/how-to-create-a-startup-webpage-in-less-than-1-hour-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-03T16:47:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2012/02/03/how-to-create-a-startup-webpage-in-less-than-1-hour-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend I attended my 3rd Startup Weekend but this time I was part of the facilitators. This one was focused on Mobile and was held at the AT&amp;T Foundry (awesome building !!).</p>




<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/startupWeekendLogo.png" alt="startupweekend" style="display:block; margin:0 auto;" title="startupweekend, mar. 2011" /></p>




<p>After being a part of <a href="http://ditchthetourbus.com" title="DitchTheTourBus">DitchTheTourBus</a> project in November 2010 during Startup Weekend Twin Cities and attenting the Mega SW in Mountain View, CA couple of months ago; I decided to help and join the SW bay team to make these events happen.</p>




<p>It's a really interesting experience to be on the other side. You can help teams to go on the right path and be focused on key points. My ultimate goal is to bring Startup Weekend in the East part of France, where there is (beside of Strasbourg) a lack of this kind of events.</p>




<p>So during the weekend I tried my best to help teams, especially teams that did not have enough time to work on app to demo or to build a website. I shared with them couple of wireframing tools like <a href="http://balsamiq.com" hreflang="en">Balsamiq</a>, <a href="https://gomockingbird.com/" hreflang="en">Mockingbird</a> or <a href="http://mockflow.com">Mockflow</a>.</p>




<p>But I also tried to make the part 2 of a previous article I wrote on my blog couple of months ago.</p>




<p>This article should help StartupWeekend teams but also small startups to create an easy nice-looking website/launch page in less than an hour.
You can find the first part of the article about which tools we are going to use here&nbsp;: <a href="http://picsoung.github.io/index.php?post/Create-a-startup-webpage-in-less-than-1-hour-Tools">create a startup webpage in less than 1 hour - tools</a></p>




<p>The second part is contains in this screencast that shows all the different steps to create your launch page.</p>




<p>Check it out :) And let me know what you think about it, feel free to ask any questions in the comment section :)</p>




<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/35448256?color=ff9933" width="400" height="250" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/35448256">HOWTO - Create a landing page for your Startup !</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/user10107911">Nicolas Grenie</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>




<p>Big shout out to <a href="http://twitter.com/siddiquiahmed" title="Ahmed ">Amed</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/JohnBeadle" title="John">John</a> who are the main organizators of SW in the Bay, also to AT&amp;T guys, SW attendees, and other facilitators&nbsp;! :)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I <3 APIs!]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/11/20/i-3-apis/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-20T18:25:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/11/20/i-3-apis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/.api1_s.jpg" alt="api1.gif" style="display:block; margin:0 auto;" title="api1.gif, déc. 2011" /></p>




<p>Give me an A ! Give me a P ! Give me an I ! API power !!</p>




<p>If that sounds like a cheerleader's song, it's totally on purpose. "API" is the new buzzworld in the tech world, with lot of fans and gurus. And you better join them now, if you don't want to be left behind.</p>




<h2>What is an API ?</h2>




<p>API stands for "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/API" hreflang="en" title="API">Application programming interface</a>" which means in a more understandable English : A hook to access a company's data/website/technology and use it in your own application.
A good way to not re-invent the wheel and to sync up with other services.</p>




<h2>Who provide APIs?</h2>




<p>As a website you want to have as much user as you can because users means business and money (not only, we agree :P) . If you have an API you will let others create their own applications on top of yours based on the datas you are willing to share.</p>




<p>For example you can use Facebook Connect platform and let your users authenticate themself throw they Facebook identity. On your side it is simpler, you get all the data directly from Facebook, no more boring form asking basic informations. From a user perspective it also easier and very smooth, one account to rule them all.</p>




<h2>Big players on API :</h2>




<p><a href="http://developers.facebook.com" hreflang="en" title="Facebook">Facebook</a></p>




<p><a href="http://dev.twitter.com" hreflang="en" title="Twitter">Twitter</a></p>




<p>Google Map</p>




<p>Youtube</p>




<p>Linkedin</p>




<p><a href="http://developer.klout.com/" hreflang="en" title="Klout">Klout</a>
...</p>




<h2>Why APIs are that big ?</h2>




<p>Nowadays you could not think about creating an innovative startup without using somebody's else API. As we said before you do not need to re-invent the wheel, somebody else did it before you. It saves you time, money and let you focus on bigger challenges.</p>




<p>You need a video-chat system ? use <a href="www.tokbox.com/opentok/api" hreflang="en" title="OpenTok">OpenTok</a>. You need to send SMS ? use <a href="http://twilio.com" hreflang="en" title="Twilio.com">Twilio</a>. And so on... It no more "there is an app for that" but "<strong>there is an API for that</strong>".</p>




<p>APIs are a good way to share/sell your technology and your data with others and make revenues out of it.</p>




<h2>How to find the right API ?</h2>




<p>With this growing market there is a lot of places to find the API that meets your needs. You check APIs providers like <a href="http://mashery.com" hreflang="en" title="Mashery">Mashery</a> or <a href="http://www.3scale.net" hreflang="en" title="3Scale">3Scale</a>, they help companies to maintain their API documention and servers.
There are also API directories like <a href="http://programmableweb.com" hreflang="en" title="ProgrammableWeb.com">ProgrammableWeb</a> or <a href="http://www.mashape.com/" hreflang="en" title="Mashape">Mashape</a>. There is alo <a href="www.apigee" hreflang="en" title="Apigee">Apigee</a> where you can debug APIs in a console.</p>




<p>Now that you know a bit more about APIs, it's time to code ;)</p>




<p>Go to hackathons and meet engineers that are building those awesome stuff.
<img src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/facebook-college-hackathon-done.png?w=300" alt="" /></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Hackathon we trust]]></title>
    <link href="http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/08/28/in-hackathon-we-trust/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-28T20:26:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://picsoung.github.io/blog/2011/08/28/in-hackathon-we-trust</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spread the word : Geeks are not living in caves anymore !! Or at least they going out from their caves to see the sunlight once in a while for a specific occasion. Something in between a computer science class, a LAN party, a crazy scientist lab and a networking event.</p>




<p>If you are part of the geek crowd you understood that I was talking about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackathon" hreflang="en" title="Hackathon">Hackathons</a>.</p>




<p>For those who don't know what what is it, let's make it easy :</p>




<h2>Hackathon = Hack + athon = Hack marathon</h2>




<p>Hack ? Wooo... like Hackers ? Cracking credit card, launching NASA spaceship or changing traffic lights ?</p>




<p>No, nothing like that. It is about Hacking but in a good way. People are building awesome products to solve problems or just for the fun of programming.</p>




<p>This kind of events is very tech oriented, so if you are not a programmer it could be hard to attend.
People are coming to work on their projects or to build new stuff during the event depends on the kind of event.</p>




<p>Since I moved to San Francisco I already attend to two different Hackathons. The first one was the <a href="http://hapihack.com" hreflang="en" title="HAPIHack">HAPIHack</a> weekend organized by <a href="www.tokbox.com/opentok/api" hreflang="en" title="Opentok">OpenTok</a> at their place. The principle was to create an application using at least one API from the sponsors. At the end of weekend, teams presented their work and a winner per API was designate to win the prize.</p>




<p><img src="http://hapihack.com/img/logo.png" alt="" /></p>




<p>During this <a href="http://hapihack.com" hreflang="en" title="HAPIHack">HAPIHack</a> I work with a Spanish mate (<a href="http://twitter.com/plunchete" hreflang="en" title="Plunchete">Ignacio</a>) on an application called <a href="http://facerate.cloudfoundry.com/" hreflang="en" title="FaceRate">FaceRate</a>. <a href="http://facerate.cloudfoundry.com/" hreflang="en" title="FaceRate">FaceRate</a> lets you take a picture of yourself to express your thought about a content (Video, Picture, text...), it is more powerful and meaningful than just a "like" or a "+1".</p>




<p>We used <a href="http://embed.ly" hreflang="en" title="Embed.ly">Embed.ly</a> API to display a content (215 types of content available), <a href="www.tokbox.com/opentok/api" hreflang="en" title="OpenTok API">OpenTok API</a> to take the picture and <a href="http://face.com/" hreflang="en" title="Face.com">Face.com</a> API to analyse your facial expression.</p>




<p>If you would like to try a live demo it's here (might be a bit buggy) : <a href="http://facerate.cloudfoundry.com/">http://facerate.cloudfoundry.com/</a></p>




<p>The googledoc prez :</p>




<iframe src="https://docs.google.com/present/embed?id=dzz485g_10hw78c8hs" frameborder="0" width="410" height="342"></iframe>




<p>And the Github repository if you want to fork it. <a href="https://github.com/picsoung/FaceRate" hreflang="en" title="FaceRate on GitHub">FaceRate on Github</a></p>




<p>It was a really nice adventure to work on a new project with somebody I did not know before. He initiate me to<a href="http://playframework.com" hreflang="en"> Play framework</a> that uses Java to build web applications and we were able to win two prizes, an Apple TV from embed.ly and a <a href="http://www.jawbone.com/speakers/jambox/overview" hreflang="en" title="Jambox">JamBox</a> from Face.com.</p>




<p>Hackathons are really a good time to meet people like you (coders), talk about technique, learn new APIs and tech stuff, be efficient (you need a result by the end of the weekend)...</p>




<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/.logo_superHappyDevHouse_m.jpg" alt="logo_superHappyDevHouse.png" title="logo_superHappyDevHouse.png, sept. 2011" /></p>




<p>This weekend I attend to the <a href="http://superhappydevhouse.org" hreflang="en" title="SuperHappyDevHouse">SuperHappyDevHouse</a> at the <a href="http://hackerdojo.com" title="HackerDojo">HackerDojo</a> in Mountain View, it was an afternoon+night Hackathon but without competitions or prizes. It was just for the sick of being with others instead of coding in your cave or at a coffee shop.</p>




<p>Special mentions to <a href="http://localno.de/" hreflang="en" title="Localno.de">Localno.de</a> that lets you share your localhost application easily (helpful in dev mode) and to <a href="http://popstardefense.com/play?s" hreflang="en" title="PopStar Defense"></a> for a 100% HTML5 amazing tower defense game.</p>




<p><img src="http://picsoung.github.io/public/illus_billets/hacker_dojo_logo_transparent.png" alt="hacker_dojo_logo_transparent.png" style="float:right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" title="hacker_dojo_logo_transparent.png, sept. 2011" /></p>




<p>Hackathons are the new trend around here with at least one every week. It a signs that tech people also need their events to meet others of their kind, so open your eyes more are coming ! Companies also need Hackathons where rockstars (#buzzword) developers will be able to see the limit of the API or ask for new features. And Hackers can help APIs providers in their development process.</p>




<p>So if you are a coder or a student who is learning Computer Science you should definetly attend to the next Hackathon around you, meet others geeks, eat pizza and code :)</p>




<p>PS : companies love if you hacked their API before applying for a job</p>




<p>Next Hackathons in the Valley :</p>




<p>10-11 Sept. <a href="http://plancast.com/p/5rq3/techcrunch-disrupt-sf-hackathon">Techcrunch Disrupt Hackathon</a></p>




<p>10-11 Sept. <a href="http://cleanwebhack.com/hackathon/" hreflang="en">Cleanweb</a> Hackathon about energy and environment</p>




<p>In Paris and other cities :</p>




<p>17 Sept. <a href="www.meetup.com/foursquare-API/" hreflang="en">Global Foursquare API Hackathon</a></p>




<p><em>Unfortunately this post was not reviewed by a English native speaker, so if you read something grammatically chocking please send me an email me @@ nicolasgrenie.com</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
